Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
錬金術は物質を理解分解再構築する科学なり
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
されど　万能の技にはあらず
無から有を生ずることあたわず
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
何かを得ようと欲すれば
必ず同等の代価を支払うものなり
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
これすなわち錬金術の基本　等価交換なり
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
錬金術師に禁忌あり
そは人体錬成なり
One must not commit this act.
これ何人も犯すことなかれ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
Marcoh, the man who Ed and Al met, possessed
a Philosopher's Stone, although it was incomplete.
エドたちが出会った男マルコーは
不完全ではあるが　賢者の石を持っていた
Moved by Ed's passion, Marcoh revealed the location his research data was hidden.
エドの熱意に動かされ
マルコーは研究資料の隠し場所を明かす
And so, after having his automail repaired,
Ed stood before the place Marcoh's data was located...
そして　機械鎧の修理を終えたエドは
マルコーの研究資料がある
国立中央図書館　第一分館の前に立つ
National Central Library, 1st Branch.
Dr. Marcoh's research data!!!
マルコーさんの研究資料が
It was too much effort to look for it,
so I just burnt down the whole building.
めんどくさいから　建物ごと燃やしちゃった
What did you do at Central?
セントラルで何してきたの
That's exactly what I've been explaining to you!
だから今説明してるでしょ
The Fullmetal boy found out about Marcoh's data.
鋼の坊やがマルコーの資料に気づいちゃったのよ
After I took care of that, I came back to East City to check on things, but...
そっちは始末つけたから
イーストシティの様子を見に戻ったんだけど
あいつは
How's he doing?
Gluttony?
グラトニー
I can smell... I can smell it.
におう　におうよ
There's an Ishbalan nearby that smells like blood.
血のにおいをまとったイシュヴァール人が近くにいるよ
Can I eat him?
あいつ食べていい
Sure, but eat every bit of him.
髪の毛一本残さずにね
There have been no sightings of Scar
since the case involving the Elric brothers.
スカーの目撃情報は
エルリック兄弟の一件以降皆無です
Maybe he's not in East City anymore?
もうイーストシティにはいないんじゃないっすか
I need him to be here.
いてもらわねば困る
Huh?
If I can solve the case that was left unresolved in Central, it should raise my status in the public's eye.
セントラルで持て余した事件を解決できれば
私の株も上がるというものだ
I'll take advantage of everything I can.
利用できるものはすべて利用する
Until I become the Führer and gain full authority over the military, that is.
私が大総統の地位に就いて
軍事の全権を掌握するまではね
You ought to refrain from making inappropriate remarks.
不穏当な発言は慎んだ方がよろしいかと
Yeah, I'll try.
せいぜい気をつけるとしよう
Excuse me, sir!
失礼します
There has been a report of an explosion by Merle River!
たった今　マール川で爆発が起きたと報告がありました
What?!
何っ
A gas explosion?
ガス爆発か
No idea.
分からん　近ごろ物騒だからなぁ
It's been so unsafe lately.
This belongs to Scar. There's no mistaking it.
スカーが着ていたものに間違いないと思います
Have any bodies been found?
死体は出たか
We've been searching, but...
捜索はしてますが
In any case, judging from this blood, it is safe to assume that he's dead.
どのみち　この出血では無事ではないでしょう
But still, we cannot let our guard down until we confirm his death.
しかし　死亡を確認するまで油断はできん
Second Lieutenant Havoc.
ハボック少尉
Sir?
はい
Your squad is to clear all of the rubble.
お前の隊は　瓦礫の撤去作業を進めろ
There will be no breaks, whether it be for lunch or supper.
昼も夜も休みはなしだ
Drag his body out, no matter what it takes.
なんとしてもヤツの死体を引っ張り出せ
うへぇ　勘弁してくださいよ
Give us a break.
Are you trying to kill us?
オレたちを過労死させる気ですか
Shut up!
うるさい
I can't even calm myself for a date until I see his dead body with my own eyes.
ヤツの死体をこの目で見るまで
私は落ち着いてデートもできんのだ
Yeah, okay.
ああそうですか
He got away.
逃げられちゃったわね
I didn't get to eat him...
食べ損ねた
There, there, maybe next time.
はいはい　また今度ね
Well, he probably won't be able to do anything for a while after all that.
まっ あれだけやっとけば
スカーもしばらく動けないでしょ
I'm going back to Central again.
私はまたセントラルに戻るわ
I need to report to Father about Scar.
お父様にスカーのこと　報告しとかなくちゃね
Everything's been burnt to a crisp.
きれいさっぱり焼けちまったな
Major Armstrong!
アームストロング少佐
Ah, 2nd Lt. Ross and Sergeant Brosh.
ロス少尉にブロッシュ軍曹ではないか
What's the matter?
何事かな
We've received orders from Headquarters to report.
司令部から　出頭するようにとの命令です
We will take over the escort of Sir Edward Elric.
エドワード·エルリック殿の護衛は
私たちが引き継ぐことになりました
All right, understood.
うむ　相分かった
What the heck?! Just when I thought I'd get rid of this smothering guy for good, I get more escorts?!
なんだよ　暑苦しいおっさんと別れられると思ったら
また護衛付きかよ
There is someone well-versed in the data that was in the Library's 1st Branch.
図書館の件ですが
第一分館の資料に精通している人物がいるとのことです
Although she is no longer employed...
もっとも　退職しているのですが
Looks like I shouldn't expect much.
期待薄そうだな
Can I help you?
何か
U-Umm...
あ　あの
Pardon my impudence, but why are you wearing a suit of armor?
ぶしつけな質問ですが　なぜ鎧のお姿で
Just a hobby!
趣味で
"Hobby"? Second Lieutenant, what kind of hobby is it?!
趣味って
少尉殿　趣味ってなんでありますか
なんなのこの子たちは
What's wrong with these kids?!
Man, Al, the scenery is great!
ああ　アル
きれいな風景だなぁ
You're right, Brother!
そうだねぇ　兄さん
Wha-
なっなんだ　この本の山
What's with these mountains of books?!
Is there really someone living here?
本当に人が住んでるんですか
Miss Sheska, are you in?
シェスカさん　いらっしゃいませんか
Miss Sheska!
シェスカさん
誰か
Someone...
Help me...
助けて
Huh?
Hm?
Brother, someone...
兄さん　人
Someone is buried under the books!
人が埋まってる
掘れ 掘れ 掘れ ここ掘れ
Dig! Dig! Dig! Dig over here!
バカ
PLACEHOLDER
Idiot!!
Hang in there!
しっかりしろ
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
すみません　すみません
うっかり本の山を崩してしまって
I carelessly knocked over a mountain of books...
このまま死ぬかと思いました
I thought that was the end for me!
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました
So you're Sheska?
あんたがシェスカ
Yes.
はい
The one who was at the 1st Branch?
第一分館にいた
1st Branch!
第一分館
Ah, even the name gives off a sweet sound!
なんて甘美な響きなんでしょう
I've always loved books ever since I was born, and I felt like I was being sent to Heaven when I got a job there.
生まれたときから本が好きで
あそこに就職が決まったときには
天にも昇るような気持ちでした
But I forgot that I was at work and was fired because I was reading all the time.
でも　仕事中だということを忘れて
本ばかり読んでいたもので　クビになってしまい
Even though I need a job to send
my sick mother to a better hospital...
病気の母をもっといい病院に入れてあげたいから
働かなくちゃいけないというのに
あぁ 本当に私ってば
Seriously... I've got no skills besides reading, and I can't find a job no matter where I go...
本を読む以外は何をやっても鈍臭くて
どこに行っても仕事ももらえなくて
That's right! I'm a failure! I'm the trash of society!
そうよ　ダメ人間だわ
社会のクズなのよう
あの　ちょっと聞きたいんだけどさ
Umm... I've got something I want to ask you...
はい
Yes?
Do you happen to know of any
research documents by Tim Marcoh?
ティム·マルコー名義の研究書に心当たりあるかな
Tim Marcoh... Tim Marcoh...
ティム·マルコーティム·マルコー
ああ　はい　覚えています
Oh! Yes, I do remember!
Really?!
ほんと
I remember it clearly because it was handwritten and shoved into a shelf in the wrong section.
手書きで
しかも分野が違う本棚に乱暴に突っ込んであったんで
よく覚えています
So it really was there...
本当にあったんだ
...which means that it's ashes now...
ってことはやっぱり丸焼けかよ
その研究書読みたいんですか
Did you want to read the research?
そうだけど　焼けちまったぁ
Yeah, but it's gone now...
どうもおじゃましました
Sorry to bother you.
I remember everything in it, though.
私　中身全部覚えてますけど
What?!
いえ　だから
W-Well, I remember the content of every book that I've ever read.
一度読んだ本の内容は全部覚えてます
時間が掛かりますけど複写しましょうか
It'll take a while, but would you like me to transcribe it?
Thank you so much, bookworm!
ありがとう　本の虫
虫ですか
...Worm?
Here is the duplicate of Mr. Tim Marcoh's research!
ティム·マルコー氏の研究書の複写です
Sorry, it took five days because there was just so much to write down.
すみません
かなりの量だったもので５日も掛かってしまいました
There really are amazing people in this world, aren't there, Brother?
世の中すごい人がいるもんだね　兄さん
Is this really Dr. Marcoh's research?
これ　本当にマルコーさんの
Yes! No doubt about it!
はい　間違いありません
"1000 Meals for Daily Living", written by Tim Marcoh.
ティム·マルコー著　「今日の献立1000種」です
Huh?
"Add a bit of water to a tablespoon of sugar"...
「砂糖 大さじ１に　水少々を加え」
These really are 1000 meals for daily living.
本当に今日の献立1000種だわ
Hey! What part this makes it an important document?!
君　これのどこが重要書類なんだね
But... all I did was copy things down exactly as I'd remembered!
そんなこと言われても　私は覚えたまま写しただけです
Looks like we just went on a wild goose chase.
どうやら　とんだ無駄足だったようですね
This is word for word what Dr. Marcoh wrote, right?
これ　マルコーさんの書いたものと
一字一句間違いないんだな
はい　間違いありません
Yes! Without a doubt.
You're amazing. Thanks a lot.
あんたすげぇよ　ありがとな
Okay! Let's take this back to the Central Library.
よし　これ持って中央図書館に戻ろう
うん　あそこなら関連書がそろってるしね
Yeah. They've got a lot of related books there, too.
ああ
Yep.
Oops. I need to reward you for all that work.
おっと　お礼お礼っと
2nd Lt. Ross, this is my registration code
and silver pocket watch as ID.
ロス少尉
これ　オレの登録コードと身分証明の銀時計
Withdraw the amount written on there from
my annual research expenditures and give it to Sheska.
オレの年間研究費から
そんだけ引き出して　シェスカに渡してあげて
Okay, so I just have to go to the state alchemist facility at the Führer administrative building, right?
はあ　大総統府の国家錬金術師機関に行けば
よろしいんですね
Yep!
そういうこと
Thanks again, Sheska!
シェスカ　ほんとにありがとな
Later!
んじゃ
Hmm, so from his research expenditures...
研究費から
うわっ　なんですかこの金額
What's with this number?!
He can just pull out a sum like this as if it's nothing?! What is that boy?!
こんな額　ポンと出すなんて
なんなの　あの子は
Are these recipes really research documents for alchemy?
ほんとにこんな料理の本が　錬金術の研究書なんですか
Alchemy is dangerous when abused.
錬金術って　悪用すると危険な技術なんだぜ
To prevent that, alchemists encrypt their research.
それを防ぐには
錬金術研究の暗号化だ
一般人にはただの料理研究に見えても
An ordinary person may think it's just a cooking experiment; only the one who wrote it will understand the content.
その中身は書いた本人にしか分からない
Basically, it's an advanced alchemy document.
高度な錬金術書ってわけさ
本人にしか分からないって
How are you going to decipher it
if only the author can understand it?
そんなのどうやって解読するんですか
Knowledge and inspiration.
知識とひらめき
The rest of it will all be busy work with patience.
あとは　ひたすら根気の作業だな
Wow, this'll take a while...
気が遠くなりそうですね
Al, there's something about a pigeon dish!
アル　ハト料理の項目があるぞ
Pigeon? Could that be...
ハト　それってもしかして
Yeah.
ああ　緑の獅子　哲学者の月のことかもしれない
It could be about the Green Lion. The philosopher's moon.
Did you bring Flamel's manuscripts
or books on Lambspring's philosopher's stone?
フランメルの古写本か
ラムズプリングの賢者の石について持ってきたか
Of course!
もちろん
Great. Hey, look here.
よし　ほらここ
Hmm?
This has to do with it, too, doesn't it?
ここもそうだろ
あっそうだね　こことかもね
Yeah, you're right! This one, too.
Yep. All right, let's give it a shot!
ああ　よし　やってやるぜ
何なんだこのクソ難解な暗号は
Why is this encryption hard as hell...
Don't you think it'll be faster to just ask Dr. Marcoh himself...
兄さん
これマルコーさんに直接聞いた方がいいんじゃあ
いや　聞いたら負けになる
No! If we ask him, we lose!
Is that the problem here?
そういう問題なの
あの
Umm...
Sheska.
シェスカ
I was able to transfer my mother to a wonderful hospital thanks to you.
エドワードさんのお陰で
母を立派な病院に移すことができました
I really appreciate it.
ありがとうございました
ああ　いいっていいって
No problem at all.
Any progress on the decoding?
解読の方は進みましたか
どよん
Have you found a job?
君は仕事見つかった
どよん
But thanks to you two, I realized that even a failure like me can be useful to others.
でもお二人のお陰で　ダメ人間の私でも
人の役に立てるんだって思えました
Thank you so much.
ありがとうございました
You're not a failure at all.
ダメ人間じゃないよ
何かに一生懸命になれるってことは
I believe being able to wholeheartedly commit yourself to something is a talent in itself,
それ自体が才能だと思うし
and you have an amazing memory.
それにすごい記憶力がある
You should have more confidence in yourself.
自信持っていいと思うよ
Thanks.
ありがとう
Yo!
よっ
Lt. Colonel Hughes!
ヒューズ中佐
アームストロング少佐に聞いたぞ
I heard from Major Armstrong you guys were back.
Come on... I told you guys to come
say hi when you stopped by Central again.
なんだよ
セントラルに来たら声掛けろって言ったのによ
Sorry, I had urgent matters to take care of.
いや　急ぎの用があってさ
まあ　オレも忙しくて
Yeah, I've been kind of busy too...
He's chatting to Lt. Colonel Hughes like they're buddies!
あのヒューズ中佐とタメ口ですよ
何なのよ　あの子たちは
What are those boys?
最近　事件やらなんやら多くってなぁ
There's been a lot of incidents and such lately.
The case with Tucker and the chimera hasn't been solved yet, either...
タッカーの合成獣事件もまだ片づいてないし
Oh... sorry.
あっ　っとすまねぇ
I made you remember it.
嫌なことを思い出させちまったな
Well, you know.
しかしあれだ　ただでさえ忙しいところにもってきて
It's busy enough, and the 1st Branch of the library just had to burn down.
第一分館も丸焼けになっちまってよ
The 1st Branch?
第一分館
Yeah. We kept a lot of case records and whatnot in the archives, so it really messes with our job.
ああ
あそこの書庫にゃあ
事件の記録やなんやら保管してたから
業務に差し支えて大変だよ
Hm? What?
ん どうした
へえ
ええ
What do you think, Lt. Colonel?
どうだろう　中佐
This woman is looking for a job.
この人　働き口探してるんだけど
Yes, I have read army criminal records and remember them, but...
確かに　軍の刑事記録も読んで覚えてますけど
All right! Let's get you set up right away!
よっしゃ　今すぐ手続きだ
We pay really well!
うちは給料いいぞ
ええっ　そんな　あの
That's... umm...
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます
I'm going to have more confidence in myself, and I'll try my best.
自信持って頑張ってみます
Thank you so much!
本当にありがとう
Come on! I need you to get to work right away.
ほらほら　早速仕事だ
What is he, a kidnapper?
人さらいか　あのおっさん
"I believe being able to wholeheartedly commit yourself to something is a talent in itself", huh...
何かに一生懸命になれるってことは
それ自体が才能か
Wise words, little bro.
言ってくれるねぇ弟よ
I really feel that way, especially when I look at a certain someone.
どっかの誰かさんを見てるとね
心の底からそう思うよ
そんじゃ　そのどっかの誰かさんは
Then that certain someone's going to keep working hard.
引き続き一生懸命やるとしますよ
Oops.
Closing time.
閉館時間ね
It's been ten days already.
今日でまるまる１０日ですよ
I can't believe they have the fortitude
to work every day until this place closes.
閉館まで　よく根気が持ちますね
ふざけんな
Bullshit!!!
兄弟ゲンカですか
Sibling fight?
You shouldn't get desperate simply because you can't solve it...
解けないからといって　自暴自棄になっては
We did solve it.
解けたんです
解けてしまったんですよ　暗号
We solved the code.
Seriously? That's great!
ほんとですか　よかったじゃないですか
いいことあるか　ちくしょう
Hell no, it's not great!
悪魔の研究　求めてはならないもの
"The Devil's research"...
"Something you mustn't desire"...
I resent you, Dr. Marcoh...
恨むぜ　マルコーさんよ
What... exactly...
一体何が
賢者の石の材料は
The ingredients of philosopher's stones...
生きた人間だ
...are live humans.
And on top of that, you need several sacrifices just to refine one stone.
しかも石を１個精製するのに
複数の犠牲が必要ってことだ
I would have never thought something so inhumane was going on in the army...
そんな非人道的なことが軍で行われてたなんて
That's something that can't be forgiven.
許されることじゃないでしょう
Could you please not tell anyone about this?
このことは誰にも言わないでくれないか
But...
しかし
Please!
頼む
Forget about it.
聞かなかったことにしといてくれ
What...
なんと
エルリック兄弟は今日も部屋に閉じこもっている
The Elric brothers have locked themselves in their room again today?
ええ　食事もろくに取らずに
Yes. They haven't eaten much, either.
Perhaps they were really tired?
疲れがたまっていたのだろうか
Seems they've been working extremely hard these past days, too.
このところ根を詰めておったようだしな
I mean, if that's  what they found after all of that difficult deciphering...
苦労して解読した資料の内容があれじゃあ
Even I start feeling sick when I start thinking about it.
オレも思い出しただけで　胸くそが悪くなりますよ
What is it?
なんだ
N-Nothing!
な　なんでもありません
Sounds fishy!
あやしい
Brother, go get something to eat.
兄さん　ご飯食べに行っといでよ
I'm not hungry.
いらん
しんどいな
This is tough.
うん
Yeah.
なんかこう
It's like...
Right when you get within arm's reach, it runs away...
手の届く所に来たなと思ったら　逃げられて
やっとの思いでつかんだら
...and when you finally grab it, it kicks you down.
つかんだそいつに蹴落とされてさ
God must really hate humans who have committed taboo.
神様は禁忌を犯した人間をとことん嫌うらしい
I wonder if we'll be like this for the rest of our lives...
オレたち　一生このままかな
Hey... there's something I've always wanted to ask you...
オレさ　ずっとお前に言おうと思ってたけど
怖くて言えなかったことがあるんだ
...but I've been too scared to.
What is it?
何
Elric brothers! You're there, aren't you?
エルリック兄弟
いるのであろう
我が輩だ　ここを開けんか
It's me. Open up!
What should we do...
どうしよう
Just ignore him.
シカトだ　シカト
I heard the whole story, Edward Elric!
聞いたぞ　エドワード·エルリック
なんたる悲劇
What a tragedy!
賢者の石に
To think that such a horrifying secret laid beneath the philosopher's stone!
そのような恐るべき秘密が隠されていようとは
S... Sorry...
ご　ごめんなさい
あんな暑苦しい人に詰め寄られたら
Not much we could do when such
a smothering person approaches you...
軍がそのようなことを行っていたとは
To think the army had been doing such a thing...
真実とは時として残酷なものよ
The truth can be cruel at times.
Truth...
真実
What's wrong, Brother?
どうしたの　兄さん
マルコーさんの言葉　覚えてるか
Do you remember Dr. Marcoh's words?
Huh?
"You may be able to reach
the real truth that is beyond truth..."
君ならば　真実の奥の更なる真実に
The real truth beyond truth...
真実の奥の更なる真実
Same as a research document for alchemy.
錬金術の研究書と一緒だ
表面に見えることは真実の一部でしかない
What can be seen from the outside is only a portion of the truth.
There's still something else!
まだ何かあるんだ　まだ
Something...
There are currently four alchemy research laboratories owned by the government within Central.
現在　政府関連の錬金術研究所は
セントラル市内に４か所ある
The one Dr. Marcoh belonged to is Research Laboratory 3.
そのうち　マルコー氏が所属していたのは第三研究所だ
This one is the most suspicious.
ここが　いちばん怪しい
We went around to every research lab in the city,
but this one wasn't particularly...
市内の研究所は全部回ってみたけど
ここはそんなに大した研究は
あっこれ　この建物は
This. What's this building?
That would be Research Laboratory 5,
but it's not being used right now.
第五研究所ですが
現在は使用されていません
No one is allowed to enter it due to risk of collapse.
崩壊の危険性があるので　立ち入り禁止になっています
This is the place.
ここだ
What makes you say that?
えっ　なんの確証があって
There's a prison right next to it.
隣に刑務所がある
And...
それが
Do you remember what's needed to create philosopher's stones?
賢者の石の材料はなんだった
Umm... was it live humans...
えっと　生きた人間
There are bound to be people on the death row at the prison.
刑務所には死刑囚もいるだろう
They tell the public they were executed, and...
表向きは処刑したことにして
Don't tell me... the prisoners are the ingredients?
まさか　囚人が材料
Don't make that face.
そんな顔しないでくれよ
オレだって考えたくねぇんだ
I don't want to think about it, either.
The prison is under a different
jurisdiction, but if it's involved...
所轄が違う刑務所が絡んでるとなると
Does this mean the government has something to do with it?
政府が関係してるのかな
I feel like I've stuck my nose into something horrible...
なんだか
とんでもないことに首を突っ込んでしまった気が
That's why we asked you to forget about it!
だから　聞かなかったことにしてって言ったでしょう
This may turn into a political matter.
これは　高度に政治的な問題になるやもしれん
I'll look into it.
我が輩が探りを入れてみる
But until then, the 2nd Lt. and
the Sergeant are not to speak of it!
それまで　少尉と軍曹はこのこと他言無用
Yes, sir!
はっ
You two better not do anything, either.
エルリック兄弟はおとなしくしてるのだぞ
You two were thinking of sneaking into the building to check it out, weren't you!!
さてはお前たち
この建物に忍び込んで
中を調べようかと思っておったな
We weren't! We weren't!
思ってない　思ってない
We were.
なんつってね
A guard at an unused building, eh?
使ってない建物に門番ねぇ
Pretty suspicious.
怪しいね
How should we get in?
どうやって入る
How about we just make an entrance?
入り口作っちまおうか
錬成反応の光で気づかれちゃうよ
They'll notice the flash of the transmutation response.
In that case...
となると
Here we... go!
よい　しょ
This place is completely shut down, too.
ここも　がっちり閉鎖かよ
Al, wait here.
アル　ここで待ってろ
Will you be all right on your own?
一人で大丈夫
大丈夫も何も　お前のでかい図体じゃここ通れないだろ
Either way, you can't get through here with that big body of yours, can you?
Not like I chose to have a big body!
好きででかくなったんじゃないやい
66.
What, 48?
なんだ ４８
Our first guest in quite a while.
久しぶりの客人だ
What a reckless dumbass.
命知らずのバカ野郎だな
This is narrower than I'd thought, dammit.
思ったより狭ぇな　ちくしょ
こりゃ普通のサイズじゃ通れなかったな
I probably wouldn't have been able to get through if I was normal-sized.
Good thing I'm small.
体小さくてよかった
Crap! I called myself small!!!
自分で小さいなんて言っちまったぁ
The lights are on.
明かりがついてる
Not being used right now my ass.
何が現在使われておりませんだ
Bingo.
ビンゴだぜ
Brother sure is taking his time...
兄さん　遅いな
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
剣に誇りを持つ者がいた
There was a man who held pride in his swordsmanship,
自らを異端と知る者がいた
and there was also another man who understood he was a heretic.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
The residents of darkness jeer, and
the blades that drank blood are shrieking.
闇の住人たちが笑い
血を吸った刃が咆哮する
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第八話　第五研究所
Episode 8, The Fifth Laboratory.
戦いに快楽を求め
Ones who seek pleasure in fighting and continue to live forever...
極限に生を感じる者たちよ
汝らの名を示せ
...speak thy names.